### Contact

nicoledillard27@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nicoled-126215a5 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Time Management Organization Skills Microsoft Word

### Languages

Spanish

### Certifications

Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support

Basic Life Support for Healthcare Providers

# Nicole D

ED RN of 6 years at Houston Methodist

Houston, Texas

# Summary

Emergency Department RN currently working in the Emergency Room at Houston Methodist in the Medical Center. I have been an ER nurse for about 6 years. Started my Career in Houston, then in December 2016 started travel nursing and recently just moved back to Houston from my last assignment in NYC. Currently completing my Master's in Nursing for the Family Nurse Practitioner Program at the Cizik School of Nursing. Projected Graduation in December 2021.

# Experience

Houston Methodist ED RN

January 2019 - Present (1 year 7 months)

**Texas Medical Center** 

42 bed ED with seperate psych ED

#1 Hospital in Texas

\*Hospital that transplants all organs

\*Many LVAD patients frequent this ED

\*Also many transplant and cancer patients frequent this ED

\*Magnet Recognized Facility

NewYork-Presbyterian Hospital
Travel ER RN

September 2018 - December 2018 (4 months)

Manhattan, New York

30 bed ED including a 6 bed pediatric ED

<sup>\*#1</sup> Hospital in New York

<sup>\*</sup>Physicians who work here are faculty at Weill Cornell Medical College

<sup>\*</sup>Many Stroke patients frequent this ED

<sup>\*</sup>Responsible for stabilizing and transferring patients

Orlando Health

Travel ER RN

March 2018 - September 2018 (7 months)

Orlando Regional Medical Center

Level I Trauma Center with 78 ED beds, Acute Care Hospital with 808 beds Travel Emergency Department Nurse

- \*Magnet Recognized Facility
- \*Comprehensive Stroke Center
- \*Burn Center
- \*Silver-level Beacon Awards for Excellence from the American Association of Critical-Care Nurses

**UT Southwestern Medical Center** 

Travel ER RN

December 2017 - March 2018 (4 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Acute Care Hospital with 40 ED beds, Teaching hospital and Research Hospital

Travel Emergency Department Nurse

- \*Transplant Center, high volume of transplant patients
- \* Many Cancer patients and LVAD patients frequent this ED
- \* Comprehensive Stroke Center
- \*Magnet recognized hospital

#### Lee Health

Travel ER RN

January 2017 - November 2017 (11 months)

Fort Myers, Florida Area

Worked at all the four hospitals of Lee Health System including: Cape Coral Hospital, Lee Memorial Hospital (Level II Trauma Center), Gulf Coast Medical Center and Health Park Medical Center.

**Emergency Department Staffing Resource Nurse** 

- \*Assisted Emergency Departments that needed help with staffing needs
- \*Received numerous Spirit awards from coworkers for showing work skills that exceeded expectations

**HCA** Healthcare

2 years 1 month

### **ER RN**

May 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 8 months)

Pearland Medical Center

Acute Care Hospital with 12 ED beds

**Emergency Department Staff Nurse** 

- \*Assisted as preceptor for new hires as needed
- \*Acted as relief charge nurse as needed
- \*Worked with Director of ED and Assistant Nurse Managers to implement changes to Improve speed and efficiency of patient care

### **ER RN**

December 2014 - May 2015 (6 months)

**Bayshore Medical Center** 

Level III Trauma Center with 22 ED beds

**Emergency Department Staff Nurse** 

- \*Responsible for stabilization and transfer of patients
- \*Mentored new employees to the unit

### Education

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston (UTHealth)

Master of Science - MS, Nurse practitioner · (2019 - 2021)

The University of Texas at Arlington

Bachelor of Science - BS, Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2014 - 2017)

Lone Star College System

Associate of Science (A.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2009 - 2014)

New Caney High School

Diploma · (2007 - 2011)